{
    "id": "0f55241a54f745bc8798c82a5a9ec678",
    "title": "Relative Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The man ………………………. lives next door is an artist.",
            "description": "We use who to refer to people.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Everyone congratulated the boy …………………………. had won the first prize.",
            "description": "When the relative pronoun is the subject of the relative clause, we use who to refer to people. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Where is the person ........................................ wanted to meet the manager?",
            "description": "When the relative pronoun is the subject of the relative clause, we use who to refer to people.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We bought some mangoes from ………………………… we extracted the juice.",
            "description": "In relative clauses which is used to refer to inanimate objects. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She is the only politician ……………………….. I really admire.",
            "description": "Here the relative pronoun is the object of the relative clause hence we use whom. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The woman .................................... diamonds had been stolen complained to the police.",
            "description": "In relative clauses whose replaces words like her or his.",
            "answers": [
                "who's",
                "whose",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I know a girl ……………………….. eyes are as deep as the ocean.",
            "description": "In relative clauses whose replaces words like her or his.",
            "answers": [
                "whose",
                "who's",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The man .................................... sits in that corner is a writer.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Who is that girl ………………………… danced with your brother?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I talked to the boy ………………………….. everyone seemed to ignore.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The used car …………………………. I bought last week is not very fuel efficient.",
            "description": "In identifying relative clauses either that or which can be used to refer to objects.",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "what"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The man …………………………. they labelled traitor is actually a patriot.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}